In this video we're going to talk about simple tables an important data structure
在本视频中，我们将讨论简单的表，这是一种重要的数据结构
in many filers before we talk about what a simple table is I want to talk about a
在许多文件管理器中，在我们讨论什么是简单的表之前，我想先谈谈
generic algorithm that we're going to be seeing instances of over and over again
通用算法，我们将一遍又一遍地看到它的实例
for the rest of the course. So, a lot of semantic analysis and in fact, a lot of
关于这门课程的睡觉。所以，进行了大量的语义分析，事实上，很多
code generation can be expressed as a recursive descent of an abstract syntax
代码生成可以表示为抽象语法的递归下降
tree. And the basic idea is that in each step we do the following three things:
树。其基本思路是，在每一步中，我们做以下三件事：
we're always processing a particular node in the tree, so if I draw a picture of the
我们总是在处理树中的特定节点，所以如果我画一张
abstract syntax tree it might have a node and some sub-trees hanging off of it. And
抽象语法树它可能有一个节点和一些挂在其上的子树。和
we may do some processing of the node before we do anything else. We arrive at
在执行任何其他操作之前，我们可能会对节点进行一些处理。我们到达的地点是
the node say from the parents, we come to here for the parent, we do some processing
节点从父节点说，我们来这里是为了父节点，我们做一些处理
in the node and I'm just indicating that by coloring it blue to indicate that we
我只是通过把它涂成蓝色来表示我们
did something here. And then we go off and we process the children. Okay. And after
在这里做了些什么。然后我们出发处理孩子们。好吧。在此之后
we process the children, after we come back to the node, we do something else. We
我们处理子节点，在我们回到节点之后，我们做一些其他的事情。我们
may do some post processing of the node, and then we return. And of course, at the
可能会对节点进行一些后期处理，然后我们返回。当然，在
same time, when we've gone off and processed the children, then we're
同时，当我们处理完孩子们之后，我们就
processing all their nodes in the same pre imposed fashion, so they're getting the
以相同的预先设置的方式处理它们的所有节点，因此它们将获得
same treatment, with some stuff being done before each node is touched, and some
相同的处理方式，在接触每个节点之前先做一些事情，然后再做一些事情
stuff being done after all their children have been processed. Okay. And. There are
在他们所有的孩子都被处理完之后才做的事情。好吧。和。确实有
many, many examples of this kind of an algorithm. This is called a recursive
这种算法的例子很多，很多。这称为递归
descent traversal of a tree. There are some instances in which we'll only process
树的下降遍历。在某些情况下，我们只会处理
each note before we process the children. Some where we only process each note after
在我们处理孩子们之前，每张纸条。在某些情况下，我们只在之后处理每一张纸条
we process all the children. Some where we do both as illustrated here in this little
我们处理所有的孩子。有些地方我们既做了又做了，就像这里这个小插图中所说明的那样
diagram And returning to the main topic of this particular video. When we're
图表，并返回到此特定视频的主要主题。当我们在
performing semantic analysis on a portion of the abstract syntax tree, we're going
对抽象语法树的一部分执行语义分析，我们将
to know, need to know which identifiers are defined. Which identifiers are in
要了解这一点，需要知道定义了哪些标识符。哪些标识符位于
scope? An exam ple of this kind of recursive descent strategy is how we can
范围呢？这种递归下降策略的一个例子是我们如何
process let bindings to track the set of variables that are in the scope. So we
进程让绑定跟踪作用域中的变量集。所以我们
have our let node in the fx syntax tree and in one sub tree we have the
将我们的let节点放在FX语法树中，在一个子树中有
initialization, and in the other sub tree we have e, the body of the let, and then
初始化，在另一个子树中有e，即字母的主体，然后
this is a let for some particular variable, and let's just write that
这是某个特定变量的字母，我们就这样写吧
variable inside the parent node here. And so, when we begin processing of this O,
在这里的父节点内的变量。所以，当我们开始处理这个O时，
just imagine that we're coming from above. So we're doing this. We're processing the
想象一下我们是从上面来的。所以我们要这么做。我们正在处理
abstract syntax tree recursively. And so we reach this point from some parent and.
递归抽象语法树。所以我们从一些家长那里得到了这一点。
There's going to be a set of symbols that are currently in scope. That, that's some
将会有一组当前在范围内的符号。那，那是一些
data structure that lives off to the side, And in fact, that's going to be our symbol
数据结构位于一边，事实上，这将是我们的标志
table And what is going to happen here? Well, the first we're going to have to do
桌子上会发生什么，这里会发生什么？嗯，首先我们要做的是
is we're going to have to process, the initializer. We're going to need to know
我们将不得不处理初始值设定项。我们需要知道
whether that's, what, whatever function we're doing on this, like type checking or
无论这是什么，不管我们在这上面做什么功能，比如类型检查或
whatever. We might get on and process that first And we'll pass the symbol table in.
管他呢。我们可能会先开始处理，然后再传入符号表。
Okay. And then we're going to process the body of the let But when we do that we're
好吧。然后我们要处理LET的主体，但是当我们这样做的时候，我们
going to pass in a set of symbols that are in scope. But now also X is now going to
将传入作用域中的一组符号。但是现在X现在也要
be in scope. So X is going to be added before we process E to the set of symbols.
在范围内。所以在我们将E添加到符号集中之前，将会添加X。
And then when we return from some expression E it's going to be removed. So,
然后当我们从某个表达式E返回时，它将被移除。所以,
it'll restore the symbol table to its previous state. So that after we leave
它会将符号表恢复到以前的状态。所以在我们离开之后
this sub tree of the abstract syntax tree, we only have the same set of symbols to
这棵抽象语法树的子树，我们只有一组相同的符号
find that we had before we entered it, So in the terminology of the three part
发现我们在进入它之前，所以在三个部分的术语中
algorithm For recursive descent that we had on the first slide. What are we doing
递归下降的算法，我们在第一张幻灯片上有过。我们在做什么？
here? Well, before we process E we are going to add the definition of X to our
这里?在我们处理E之前，我们要把X的定义加到我们的
list of current definitions. Already any other definition of X that might have been
当前定义列表。已经有任何其他对X的定义可能是
visible outside of that expression. Then we are going to recurse we going to
在该表达式之外可见。然后我们将递归，我们将
process all. Of the abstract syntax tree no des in the body of the [inaudible],
全部处理。在[听不见]的主体中没有抽象语法树的情况下，
inside of E, and after we finish processing E, we are gonna remove the
在E内部，在我们完成处理E之后，我们将删除
definition of X and restore whatever old definition of X we had. And a symbol table
X的定义，并恢复我们对X的任何旧定义。和符号表
is just a data structure that accomplishes these things. It tracks the current
只是一个完成这些任务的数据结构。它会追踪海流
bindings of identifiers at each point in the abstract syntax tree. For a very
抽象语法树中每个点的标识符绑定。对于一个非常
simple, simple table, we could just use a stack, and it would have just say the
简单，简单的表，我们可以只使用堆栈，它只会显示
following three operations, we could add a symbol. To the symbol table and that will
在三个操作之后，我们可以添加一个符号。添加到符号表中，这将
just push the symbol, push the variable onto the stack and whatever other
只需将符号推入，将变量推入堆栈或其他任何操作即可
information we want, like its type. We'll have a find symbol operation that will
我们想要的信息，比如它的类型。我们将有一个查找符号操作，它将
look up the current definition for a symbol. And that can be done by simply
查找符号的当前定义。要做到这一点，只需简单地
searching the, the stack. Starting from the top for the first occurrence of the
搜索堆栈。事件的第一个匹配项从顶部开始。
variable name, And this will automatically take care of the hiding of all
变量名，这将自动负责隐藏所有
definitions. So, for example, If we have a stack, let's say has X, Y and Z on it and
定义。例如，如果我们有一个堆栈，假设上面有X、Y和Z，
then we come into a scope that introduces a new Y. Y on top and now if we search the
然后我们进入一个在顶部引入新的Y.Y的范围，现在如果我们搜索
stack we find this y first effectively hiding the old definition of y and then.
堆栈，我们发现这个y首先有效地隐藏了y的旧定义，然后。
When we leave a scope we can remove a symbol simple popping a stack. We'll just
当我们离开一个作用域时，我们可以移除一个符号，简单地弹出一个堆栈。我们只要
pop the current variable off of this stack. That will get rid of the most
将当前变量从此堆栈中弹出。这将消除大多数
recent definition. And, and leave the stack, leave the set of definitions in the
最近的定义。然后离开堆栈，将这组定义保留在
same state it was before we entered the node at all. So, this example, if we left
与我们进入节点之前的状态相同。所以，这个例子，如果我们离开
the scope where the Y is defined and that was popped off the stack, So that was
定义Y并从堆栈中弹出的作用域，因此
gone. Now, when we search for Y we'll find the outer definition. The one that was
不见了。现在，当我们搜索Y时，我们会找到外部定义。就是那个
defined outside of that inner scope, So this simple symbol table works well for
定义在该内部作用域之外，因此这个简单的符号表可以很好地用于
let, because the symbols rate at one at a time, and because declarations are
让我们来看一下，因为符号一次只有一个的速率，而且声明是
perfectly nested. And in fact, the fact that declarations were perfectly nested is
完美的嵌套。事实上，声明被完美嵌套的事实是
really the whole reason that we can use a stack/ So, take a look at this little
我们可以使用堆栈的全部原因/所以，请看这一小部分
example, let's say we have three nested lets, and here I'm not showing the
例如，假设我们有三个嵌套的let，这里我不显示
initializers in the less sub trees, and they, they don't matter, for what I want
初始值设定项在较少的子树中，它们，它们无关紧要，因为我想要的是
to illustrate. So if you think about it as we walk from the root here down to the
来说明一下。所以当我们从这里的根部往下走的时候，如果你想一想
inner bindings, we're pushing things on the stack, we'll push things on the stack
内部绑定，我们将把东西推到堆栈上，我们会把东西推到堆栈上
in the order X, Y, and then Z. And then as we leave, after we've processed this sub
按X，Y，然后Z的顺序。然后在我们离开的时候，在我们处理完这个SUB之后
tree, and we're leaving it, walking back out, we're going to encounter these left
这棵树，我们离开它，走回去，我们会遇到这些左边的
scopes in exactly the reverse order. And popping them off the stack is exactly the
作用域的顺序正好相反。将它们从堆栈中弹出正是
order in which we want to remove them, and that's why a stack works well. So
我们想要删除它们的顺序，这就是堆栈工作良好的原因。所以
Structure works fine for lets, but for some other constructs it's not quite as
结构对于let来说工作得很好，但是对于其他一些结构就不太一样了。
good as it could be so for example consider the following piece of code.
尽管它可能是好的，例如，请考虑以下代码段。
Illegal piece of code I should add. Let's say we're declaring a method, and it has
我应该添加的非法代码片段。假设我们正在声明一个方法，它具有
two arguments named X. Now, that's not legal but in order to detect that it's not
两个名为X的参数。现在，这是不合法的，但为了检测它是不合法的
legal you. Why is it not legal? It's not legal cause they're both defined in the
合法的你。为什么这是不合法的？这是不合法的，因为它们都在
same scope. So, Functions, or methods, have the property that they introduce
同样的范围。因此，函数或方法具有它们引入的属性
multiple names at once into the same scope. And it's not quite so easy, to use
将多个名称同时放入同一作用域。而且它并不是那么容易使用的，
a stack, where we only add one thing at a time, or one name at a time, to model
一个堆栈，在该堆栈中，我们一次只向模型添加一项内容，或者一次添加一个名称
simultaneous definition in a scope. So this problem is easily solved with just a
作用域中的同时定义。所以这个问题很容易解决，只需
slightly fancier simple table. Here is the revised interface now with five methods
稍微花哨一点的简易桌。下面是修改后的界面，现在有五种方法
instead of three. The biggest change is that now we have explicit enter and exit
而不是三个。最大的变化是现在我们有了明确的进入和退出
scope functions, and so these functions start in the nested scope and exit the
作用域函数，因此这些函数在嵌套作用域中开始并退出
current scope. And the way you think about this is that our new structure is a stack
当前作用域。你可以这样想，我们的新结构是一个堆栈
of scopes, so [inaudible] is the entire scope and the inner scope. Is, are all the
作用域，所以[听不见]是整个作用域和内部作用域。就是，都是
variables that are defined at the same level, within that single scope. So just
在同一级别、在该单个作用域内定义的变量。所以只要
like before, we have a find symbol operation that will look up a variable
与前面一样，我们有一个查找符号操作，它将查找变量
name, and it will return the current definition, or null if there is no
名称，它将返回当前定义，如果没有定义，则返回NULL
definition in any scope that's currently available. We'll have an add symbol
当前可用的任何范围内的定义。我们会有一个加号
Operation that adds a new symbol to the table, and adds it in the curren t scope,
将新符号添加到表中并将其添加到Current t作用域的操作，
so whatever, scope is at the top of our scope stack. And then one more new
所以不管怎样，作用域位于我们作用域堆栈的顶部。然后又多了一个新的
operation, check scope. Will return true if X is already defined in the current
操作，检查范围。如果X已在当前
scope, So this, just to be clear what this does, this returns true if X is defined in
作用域，所以这，只是为了弄清楚它的作用，如果在X中定义了X，它将返回TRUE
exactly the top scope. It doesn't return true unless, X is defined in the scope at
正好是最上面的范围。除非在以下位置的作用域中定义了X，否则它不会返回TRUE
the very, very top of the stack. And this allows you to check for double
堆栈的最顶端。这使您可以检查重复的
definitions, So, for example, in the, code that I had before on the previous slide,
定义，例如，在我之前在上一张幻灯片上的代码中，
if we had two declarations of X. How would we check this? Well, we would add X to the
如果我们有两个X的声明，我们该如何检查呢？嗯，我们会把X加到
symbol table, in the current scope. And then we would ask, well, is X already
符号表，位于当前范围内。然后我们会问，嗯，X已经
defined in this scope for the second one? And this interface would be return true,
是否在此范围内为第二个定义？且该接口将返回TRUE，
and we would know to raise an error saying that X, had been multiply defined.
我们就会知道抛出一个错误，说X已经被多重定义了。
Finally, let me just add that this is the simple table interface or something very
最后，让我补充一下，这是一个简单的表接口或一些非常
close to this is the simple table interface that is supplied with the cool
与此接近的是随Cool一起提供的简单表格界面
project. And there's already implementation of this interface provided
项目。并且已经提供了此接口的实现
if you don't want to write your own. So let's wrap up this video by talking a
如果你不想自己写的话。那么让我们来结束这段视频，我们先来谈谈
little bit about class names, which behave quite differently from the variables
关于类名，它的行为与变量有很大的不同
introduced in let bindings and in function parameters. In particular class names can
在let绑定和函数参数中引入。具体地说，类名称可以
be used before they are defined, as we discussed a few videos ago. And what that
在定义它们之前使用它们，正如我们在前面几个视频中讨论的那样。那又是什么呢？
means is that we can't check class names, in a single pass. We can't just walk over
这意味着我们不能一次检查类名。我们不能就这么走过去
the program once. And check that every class that is used is defined because we
程序只有一次。并检查是否定义了使用的每个类，因为我们
don't know that we've seen all the definitions of the classes until we reach
在我们到达之前，我不知道我们已经看到了类的所有定义
the very end of the program. And so there is a solution to this we have to make two
节目的最后。所以这个问题有一个解决方案，我们必须做两个
passes over the program. In the first pass we gather all the class definitions, we go
跳过这个节目。在第一个过程中，我们收集了所有的类定义，然后
through and we find every place where a class is defined, record all of those
通过，我们找到定义类的每个地方，记录所有这些
names. And in the second pass we go through and look at the bodies of the
名字。在第二个过程中，我们穿过并观察
classes and make sure they only use classes that were defined. And the lesson
类，并确保它们只使用定义的类。而这一课
here, this is actually not complicated to implement I think it's quite clear. Should
在这里，这实际上实现起来并不复杂，我想这是相当清楚的。应该
be quite clear how this will work. But the message here is that semantic analysis is
要非常清楚这将如何工作。但这里要传达的信息是，语义分析
going to require multiple passes, and probably more than two. And, in fact, you
需要多次通行证，而且可能不止两次。而且，事实上，你
should not be afraid when structuring your compiler to add lots and lots of simple
在构造编译器以添加大量简单的
passes if that makes your life easier, so it's better to break something up into
如果这能让你的生活更轻松的话就算了，所以最好把一些东西分成
three or four simple passes rather than to have one very, very complicated pass where
三个或四个简单的传球，而不是一个非常，非常复杂的传球，
all the code is entangled. I think you'll find it much easier to debug your
所有的代码都是纠缠在一起的。我想您会发现调试您的
compilers if you're willing to make multiple passes over the input.
编译器，如果您愿意对输入进行多次传递的话。